<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>With Daniel Silverman (Carnegie Mellon University) and Christopher Gelpi | Daniel Kent</title>
    <link>https://dnkent.github.io/authors/with-daniel-silverman-carnegie-mellon-university-and-christopher-gelpi/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dnkent.github.io/authors/with-daniel-silverman-carnegie-mellon-university-and-christopher-gelpi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>With Daniel Silverman (Carnegie Mellon University) and Christopher Gelpi</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 14:51:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dnkent.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>With Daniel Silverman (Carnegie Mellon University) and Christopher Gelpi</title>
      <link>https://dnkent.github.io/authors/with-daniel-silverman-carnegie-mellon-university-and-christopher-gelpi/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Fears of Terrorism, Partisan Rhetoric, and the Foundations of American Interventionism</title>
      <link>https://dnkent.github.io/post/fear_terrorism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 14:51:57 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dnkent.github.io/post/fear_terrorism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An American’s yearly chance of being killed by a terrorist attack sits at about 1 in 3.5 million.
Yet over 40% of the public have been consistently found to believe they or a family member
are likely or very likely to be the victim of a terror attack. Can these heightened estimates of
the risks posed by terrorism be brought closer to reality? With trillions of dollars spent on the
War on Terror, this question is not just theoretically but practically important. To investigate,
we use an experimental approach, testing whether participants update beliefs when presented
with factual information about the risks posed by terrorism. Across survey experiments fielded on
NORC&amp;rsquo;s AmeriSpeak and Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Mechanical Turk platform we find that the overblown fear of terrorism
is indeed reducible. Moreover, treatment effects last over time, maintaining significance when participants
were recontacted two-weeks after the initial survey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
