<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>With Daniel Silverman (Carnegie Mellon University) and Christopher Gelpi | Daniel Kent</title>
    <link>https://dnkent.github.io/authors/with-daniel-silverman-carnegie-mellon-university-and-christopher-gelpi/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dnkent.github.io/authors/with-daniel-silverman-carnegie-mellon-university-and-christopher-gelpi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>With Daniel Silverman (Carnegie Mellon University) and Christopher Gelpi</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 14:51:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dnkent.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>With Daniel Silverman (Carnegie Mellon University) and Christopher Gelpi</title>
      <link>https://dnkent.github.io/authors/with-daniel-silverman-carnegie-mellon-university-and-christopher-gelpi/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Fears of Terrorism, Partisan Rhetoric, and the Foundations of American Interventionism</title>
      <link>https://dnkent.github.io/post/fear_terrorism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 14:51:57 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dnkent.github.io/post/fear_terrorism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Download the paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://dnkent.github.io/files/skg-working-paper.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An American’s yearly chance of being killed by a terrorist attack sits at roughly 1 in 3.5 million. Yet, over 40% of the American public consistently believes that they or their family members are likely to be the victim of a terror attack. Can these inflated estimates of the risks of terrorism be brought closer to reality? With trillions of dollars spent on the “War on Terror,” this question is not just theoretically but practically important. In order to investigate, we use an experimental approach assessing whether people update their core beliefs about the terror threat when given factual information about the risks it actually presents. We find that public fear of terrorism and demand for countering it can be sharply reduced with better information, dropping essentially to pre-9/11 levels after receiving the treatments and staying that way two weeks later. These results show that the American public’s exaggerated fear of terrorism – which has facilitated many of the country’s costly foreign policy decisions since 9/11 – is far more malleable and correctible than previously thought. In this sense, countering terrorism may largely require providing more context and perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
