<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>With J. Andres Gannon (UCSD) | Daniel Kent</title>
    <link>https://dnkent.github.io/authors/with-j.-andres-gannon-ucsd/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dnkent.github.io/authors/with-j.-andres-gannon-ucsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>With J. Andres Gannon (UCSD)</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 14:46:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dnkent.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>With J. Andres Gannon (UCSD)</title>
      <link>https://dnkent.github.io/authors/with-j.-andres-gannon-ucsd/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Your Friends Close, But Acquaintances Closer: Why Weakly Allied States Make Committed Coalition Partners</title>
      <link>https://dnkent.github.io/post/isaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 14:46:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dnkent.github.io/post/isaf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do states join wartime coalitions despite the absence of a salient threat or strong
ties to the coalition leader? We argue states make unexpectedly high contributions to coalition warfare
as a costly signal of their desire for a stronger relationship with the coalition
leader. Conventional theories insufficiently explain why states without immediate security
interests or strong ties to the lead state over-contribute relative to their capacity. Using
newly compiled data on troop contributions to the war in Afghanistan (2001-2014), we
find states are most likely to contribute a higher share of their armed forces when their
relationship with the US has unrealized alliance potential. States with under-performing
alignments leave substantial room for subsequent gains to be had from signaling their commitment to the leading coalition actor.
Our finding helps explain why states risk the costs
of war – casualties and domestic accountability – by participating in coalition warfare.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
